{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following bacteria lack a cell wall and are therefore resistant to penicillin?", "opta": "Cyanobacteria", "optb": "Mycoplasmas", "optc": "Bdellovibrios", "optd": "Spirochetes", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A cluster of polar flagella is called", "opta": "lophotrichous", "optb": "amphitrichous", "optc": "monotrichous", "optd": "petritrichous", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Flagella move the cell by", "opta": "many flagella beating in a synchronous, whip-like motion", "optb": "an individual flagellum beating in a whip-like motion", "optc": "spinning like a propeller", "optd": "attaching to nearby particles and contracting", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The protein from which hook and filaments of flagella are composed of, is", "opta": "keratin", "optb": "flagellin", "optc": "gelatin", "optd": "casein", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cooci which mostly occur in single or pairs are", "opta": "Streptococci", "optb": "Diplococci", "optc": "Tetracocci", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following may contain fimbriae?", "opta": "Gram-positive bacteria", "optb": "Gram-negative bacteria", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Peptidoglycan accounts for __________ of the dry weight of cell wall in many gram positive bacteria", "opta": "50% or more", "optb": "About 10%", "optc": "11%+ 0.22%", "optd": "About 20%", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bacteria having no flagella are unable to", "opta": "move", "optb": "reproduce", "optc": "stick to tissue surfaces", "optd": "grow in nutrient agar", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true about cell wall of gram-positive bacteria?", "opta": "It consists of multiple layers", "optb": "It is thicker than that associated with gram-negative bacteria", "optc": "It contains teichoic acids", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cell walls of many gram positive bacteria can be easily destroyed by the enzyme known as", "opta": "lipase", "optb": "lysozyme", "optc": "pectinase", "optd": "peroxidase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cell wall of", "opta": "gram-positive bacteria are thicker than gram-negative bacteria", "optb": "gram-negative bacteria are thicker than gram-positive bacteria", "optc": "both have same thickness but composition is different", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Peptidoglycan is also known as", "opta": "N-acetyl muramic acid", "optb": "murein mucopeptide", "optc": "N acetylglucosamine", "optd": "mesodiaminopimetic acid", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Genetic system is located in the prokaryotes in", "opta": "nucleoid", "optb": "chromatin", "optc": "nuclear material", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is most likely to be exposed on the surface of a gram-negative bacterium?", "opta": "Pore protein (porin)", "optb": "Protein involved in energy generation", "optc": "Lipoteichoic acid", "optd": "Phospholipids", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The last step in synthesis of peptidoglycan is", "opta": "attachment of a peptide to muramic acid", "optb": "attaching two amino acids to form a cross-link", "optc": "attachment of a portion of peptidoglycan to a membrane lipid", "optd": "binding of penicillin to a membrane protein", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cytoplasmic inclusions include", "opta": "ribosomes", "optb": "mesosomes", "optc": "fat globules", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cocci which forms a bunch and irregular pattern are", "opta": "Staphylococci", "optb": "diplococci", "optc": "Tetracocci", "optd": "Streptococci", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chemotaxis is a phenomenon of", "opta": "swimming away of bacteria", "optb": "swimming towards a bacteria", "optc": "swimming away or towards of bacteria in presence of chemical compound", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The structure responsible for motility of bacteria is", "opta": "pilli", "optb": "flagella", "optc": "sheath", "optd": "capsules", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The next to last step in peptidoglycan biosynthesis is", "opta": "synthesis of the NAM-peptide subunit", "optb": "removal of the subunit from bactoprenol", "optc": "linking the sugar of the disaccharide-peptide unit to the growing peptidoglycan chain", "optd": "cross-linking the peptide side chains of peptidoglycan", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cocci which forms a chain is", "opta": "Streptococci", "optb": "diplococci", "optc": "Staphylococci", "optd": "Tetracocci", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The arrangement, in which flagella are distributed all round the bacterial cell, is known as", "opta": "lophotrichous", "optb": "amphitrichous", "optc": "peritrichous", "optd": "monotrichous", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Periplasm is", "opta": "the area between the inner and outer membranes of gram-negative bacteria", "optb": "the area between the inner and outer membranes of Gram-positive bacteria", "optc": "the interior portion of mitochondria", "optd": "the area outside the cell membrane that is influenced by the polymers", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following has peptidoglycan as a major constituent of cell wall?", "opta": "Gram-negative bacteria", "optb": "Gram-positive bacteria", "optc": "Fungi", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The common word for bacteria which are helically curved rods is", "opta": "cooci", "optb": "pleomorphic", "optc": "bacillus", "optd": "spirilla", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bacteria deficient in cell wall is", "opta": "Treponema", "optb": "Mycoplasma", "optc": "Staphylococcus", "optd": "Klebsiella", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not true about peptidoglycan?", "opta": "It is a polymer consisting of N-acetyl glucosamine, N-acetyl muramic acid and amino acids (alanine, lysine, etc.)", "optb": "It is present in prokaryotic cell wall", "optc": "It occurs in the form of a bag shaped macro molecule surrounding the cytoplasm membrane", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The common word for bacteria which are spherical in shape is", "opta": "cocci", "optb": "bacilli", "optc": "spirilla", "optd": "pleomorphic", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Single or clusters of flagella at both poles is known as", "opta": "monotrichous", "optb": "petritrichous", "optc": "amphitrichous", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following bacterial genera (that produces endospore) have medical importance?", "opta": "Clostridium", "optb": "Bacillus", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Microcapsules are composed of", "opta": "proteins", "optb": "polysaccharides", "optc": "lipids", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gram positive cells have a", "opta": "second outer membrane that helps to retain the crystal violet stain", "optb": "multiple layer of peptidoglycan that helps to retain the crystal violet stain", "optc": "thick capsule that traps the crystal violet stain", "optd": "periplasmic space that traps the crystal violet", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The common word for bacteria which are straight rod in shape is", "opta": "cooci", "optb": "bacilli", "optc": "spirilla", "optd": "pleomorphic", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A single polar flagella is known as", "opta": "monotrichous", "optb": "lophotrichous", "optc": "amphitrichous", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Teichoic acids are typically found in", "opta": "cell walls of gram positive bacteria", "optb": "outer membranes of gram positive bacteria", "optc": "cell walls of gram negative bacteria", "optd": "outer membranes of gram negative bacteria", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In eukaryotic cells, ribosomes are", "opta": "70S", "optb": "60S", "optc": "80S", "optd": "Not specific", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Porins are located in", "opta": "the outer membrane of gram-negative bacteria", "optb": "the peptidoglycan layer of gram-positive bacteria", "optc": "the cytoplasmic membrane of both gram-negative and gram-positive bacteria", "optd": "the periplasmic space of gram-negative bacteria", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is exposed on the outer surface of a gram-negative bacterium?", "opta": "O-antigen of lipopolysaccharide (LPS)", "optb": "Polysaccharide portion of lipoteichoic acid (LTA)", "optc": "Braun lipoprotein", "optd": "Electron transport system components", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following does not contain protein?", "opta": "Pili", "optb": "Flagellum", "optc": "Lipoteichoic acid", "optd": "Porin", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Swimming towards a chemical of bacteria is termed as", "opta": "positive chemotaxis", "optb": "negative chemotaxis", "optc": "phototaxis", "optd": "magnetotaxis", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chemically the capsule may be", "opta": "polypeptide", "optb": "polysaccharide", "optc": "either (a) or (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Peptidoglycan is found only in the bacterial", "opta": "cell membrane", "optb": "glycocalyx", "optc": "cell wall", "optd": "spore", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cell walls of Gram positive bacteria contain two modified sugar, viz. N- acetylgucosamine (NAG) and N- acetylmuramic acid (NAM). They are covalently linked by", "opta": "\u03b1- 1,4-glycosidic bond", "optb": "\u03b2-1,6-glycosidic bond", "optc": "\u03b1- 1,6-glycosidic bond", "optd": "\u03b2- 1,4-glycosidic bond", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following organism has sterols in their cytoplasmic membrane?", "opta": "Clostridum", "optb": "Proteus", "optc": "Mycoplasma", "optd": "Bacillius", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Name the component of flagellum.", "opta": "Filament", "optb": "Hook", "optc": "Basal body", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The location where the bacterial chromosome concentrates is called", "opta": "nucleus", "optb": "nuclein", "optc": "nucleoid", "optd": "nucleose", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is analogous to mesosomes of bacteria?", "opta": "Mitochondria of eukaryotes", "optb": "Golgi apparatus of eukaryotes", "optc": "Lysosomes of eukaryotes", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following has Chinese letter arrangement?", "opta": "Bacillus anthracis", "optb": "Mycobacterium tuberculosis", "optc": "Clostridium tetani", "optd": "Corynebacterium diphtheriae", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The other name for peptidoglycan is", "opta": "mucopeptide", "optb": "murein", "optc": "both (a) & (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cyanobacteria have", "opta": "a gram-positive cell wall", "optb": "a gram-negative cell wall", "optc": "Neither (a) nor (b)", "optd": "No cell wall", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In which of the following, lipo-polysaccharide is a major constituent of outer membrane of the cellwall?", "opta": "Gram-positive bacteria", "optb": "Gram-negative bacteria", "optc": "Fungi", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following structure(s) is /are external to cell wall?", "opta": "Flagella", "optb": "Stalks", "optc": "Sheath", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following may be most likely to be missing from a gram-positive bacterium?", "opta": "Penicillin binding protein", "optb": "Peptidoglycan", "optc": "Lipopolysaccharide", "optd": "Phospholipid bilayer membrane", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}